PAULINE P. NARVAS

Leeds, UK | pauline@paulinenarvas.com | linkedin.com/in/pnarvas | paulinenarvas.com

PROFILE

Equipped with strong technical and communication skills built from 2 years on a competitive graduate scheme, 3 years as a remote web developer and 4 years developing communities. With self-development at the centre of my character, I'm continuously eager to fill gaps in my technical knowledge and skills to be the best engineer that I can be. I recently became Amazon Web Services (AWS) Certified with the Cloud Practitioner (CCP) certification. I've been listed on Code First: Girls' Top 25 under 30 in tech, Northern Power Women's Future List and J.P. Morgan's x The Tab Future 100 List.

EXPERIENCE

Digital Engineering Graduate, BT | September 2018 - Present

Two year graduate scheme, four six month rotations within BT Consumer Digital.

Rotation 4 - Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) | March 2020 - Present

- Contributed to development of the new SRE team, driving the team's long-term vision and advocating our value. This raised our profile across BT Group, and we gained backing and support from higher management.
- Contributed to the development of our cloud computing standards striving for operational excellence across BT Group. Focusing on optimizing cost, performance, reliability, and security.
- Tech includes: AWS (SNS, Lambda), CloudHealth by VMWare, Python

Key achievements:

- Drove a 21% decrease in our CIS security issues and saved \$250K annual costs on our production accounts.
- Using serverless technology, automated manual tasks that allow dev teams to focus on innovation, reliability and quality.

Rotation 3 - Platform Services | Sept 2019 - March 2020

- Standardised BT Consumer Digital's delivery pipeline for cloud infrastructure provisioning and development CI/CD workflows, promoting a consistent approach on our infrastructure.
- Assisted dev teams in integrations with our CI/CD e.g. Jenkins
- Advocated Platform Services and the power of our tools to speed up releases into production
- Tech includes: AWS, Terraform, Packer, Vault, Consul, Linux/Unix, Python, Ansible, Docker, Jenkins

Key achievements:

- Led the Single Sign On (SSO) project delivery and implementation for Slack with Jenkins and Shibboleth for BT Enterprise. Transforming the way colleagues collaborate with each other.
- Automated a long process of creating static websites. Built a self-serve service that allows colleagues to spin up
 their own static website within minutes using AWS Route 53, S3, Terraform and Jenkins. Led to faster, automated
 deployment of projects replacing the manual process of going through the AWS Management Console.

Rotation 2 - MyEE Web (Development) | March 2019 - September 2019

- Worked with remote developers in Belarus and India, using Scrum
- Contributed to several scheduled production releases for MyEE Web
- Developed Proof of Concepts that improved our current approach on automation and looked at ways to improve our current tech stack
- Tech includes: HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, git

Key achievements:

- Built new UI features including development on the Roaming and Add-ons page. Improving the user experience for the 10 million customers who are registered on MyEE.
- Led in prioritising technical debt through refactoring projects, which helped keep our large codebase clean.

Rotation 1 - Digital Architecture | September 2018 - March 2019

- Worked with stakeholders from impacted squads to gather key requirements of propositions
- Produced impact assessments with new propositions to present at the Digital IA forum
- Identified ways we can improve our digital tools, technology and architecture

Key achievement: Part of the team that looked at simplifying enterprise tooling strategy to better our ways of working. This led to the implementation of Slack which is now used as the primary internal communication tool across Digital.

Other notable contributions:

- Led the technical implementation of "Code Bootcamp" a React app where graduates can learn to code
- Featured in BT's rebrand campaign, "Beyond Limits" on their promo video
- Featured in The Yorkshire Post, The Daily Mirror, The Sheffield Star to share my career journey
- Organised a BT International Women's Day event in Leeds, bringing together women from the local community
- Organised a "Techy Tea party" with Leeds Library to help grow essential digital skills for the general public
- Organised a BT Hack Day with the University of Leeds to promote BT's new technical direction and inspire innovation in students

Remote Web Developer, The University of Sheffield | November 2017 - May 2020

- Developed an independent research-focused website for PhD students and research fellows.
- Continuous improvement with new features, site optimisation and general maintenance of the website that continues to engage researchers internationally.

Key achievement: Implemented Wordpress for research fellows to share their research and contribution, improving visibility of their work across higher education at a global scale.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2016 2019: Organiser, Ambassador and Lead Instructor, Code First: Girls
- 2017 2018: Enterprise Intern, The University of Sheffield Enterprise (USE)
- 2017 2018: HackMed Hackathon Organiser, MedTech Sheffield
- 2016 2017: Communications and External Engagement Assistant Intern, The University of Sheffield

SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

- Amazon Web Services Qualified: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CCP)
- Web Development: HTML, CSS/SASS, Javascript, jquery, React, Nextjs, PHP, Wordpress
- **DevOps:** Jenkins, Terraform, Packer, Ansible, Python, Docker
- **Engagement optimisation:** I grew my online blog from 127 unique visitors in 2015 to 5, 471 in 2019.
- **Confident public speaker:** Most notably as a keynote speaker at GitHub Field Day in 2017, expert speaker at "Grow from Your STEM" Gov event in 2018, panelist at DevOps Leeds in 2019 and BT Group's IWD event in 2020.
- Passionate community builder: brought together tech communities including over 300 Code First: Girls students, HackSheffield and HackMed (where there was a 50/50 M:F ratio in attendees, many who were CF:G students.)

EDUCATION

The University of Sheffield | 2014 - 2018

BSc (Hons) Biomedical Sciences with Employment Experience

Tapton School | 2008 - 2014

3 A Levels: Biology, Chemistry and Sociology 12 A*-C GCSEs including Maths, English and Triple Science

REFERENCES

Available upon request